# Hannah McCullough

mccullough.hannah@outlook.com | (602) 903-0852 | Portfolio | GitHub

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Innovative full-stack software engineer with skills in building applications & APIs with a user-experience approach. Having a curious mind and a background in customer service, management, and athletics, I bring strong skills in client relations, collaboration, and leadership.

## **SKILLS**

React, JavaScript, RESTful APIs, Node, TypeScript, UI/UX Design, Python, Git, Content Management Systems, BaaS, MongoDB, Rails, Tailwind CSS, NPM, HTML, CSS, Next, Bootstrap, Docker, SQLite

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance Phoenix, AZ
Web Developer 01/2018 – Present

- Collaboratively develop full-stack, responsive web applications based on product design specifications utilizing React, JavaScript, TypeScript, Tailwind CSS, & Rails
- Model custom database schemas and RESTful APIs with Rails, Active Record, & PostgresSQL
- Scope & create user stories in a collaborative team setting with product guidance
- Design, develop, launch, & support responsive web applications for businesses resulting in increased traffic & leads

## Synapse Financial Technologies

Software Engineer II

San Francisco, CA (remote) 07/2022 – 10/2023

- Served as team lead providing technical guidance, mentorship, and knowledge to teammates
- Implemented client direct request, quick turnaround feature enhancements in Python RESTful APIs
- Used strong troubleshooting & bug resolution abilities to quickly rectify production API issues using DataDog, EKS, and Postman
- Managed internal & external developer documentation in Confluence that provided a deeper understanding of the technical side of the products & implementations
- Provided consistent results via strong program design & management skills utilizing Jira & LucidChart
- Improved cross-team processes by providing feedback and alternative solutions to leadership, which positively impacted client experience integration changes

USAA Phoenix, AZ Insurance Professional I 09/2018 – 11/2021

- Served as a department facilitator in the Pulse initiative by communicating employee feedback & innovation to executives
- Regularly facilitated team meetings, resulting in an overall increase in team metrics

## **EDUCATION**

Saint Francis University/
Lake Erie college
08/2010 - 05/2014
Bachelor of Arts in Psychology
Athlete

Scottsdale Community College 08/2018 - 12/2022

Associates in Applied Science -

- Web Development
- Web Design

Flatiron School

11/2021 - 03/2022

Certificate

Full-Stack Software Engineering